

ORNELLA FAZZITO

ENGLISH <> SPANISH TRANSLATOR

• DETAILS •

♥ Montevideo, Uruguay ■ orne.fazzito@gmail.com

> Date of birth 12-28-1994

∘ LINKEDIN ∘

in in/ornella-fazzito/

∘ PORTFOLIO ∘

arnella-fazzito.github.com

SOFT SKILLS

Fast Learner

Adaptability

Communication Skills

Critical Thinking

Collaboration

Time Management

HARD SKILLS

Google Suite

Microsoft Office Suite

SDL Trados

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

Portuguese

PROFILE

I am a versatile person with excellent organizational skills and more than 5 years of experience in company roles. I believe in team work and in constantly learning new things for personal and professional growth. Strong communication and strategic planning abilities are one of my key skills. I am not only a dedicated contributor but also a keen observer, always open to absorbing insights from my colleagues to enhance my own skill set.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Team Lead at Homeland Language Services, United States

March 2022 - Present

- Drive efficiency and effectiveness of the team
- Monitor performance
- Liaising with the HR & Operations team to find solutions in the long term
- Taking initiative to improve processes and implement changes

English-Spanish Interpreter at Homeland Language Services, United States

December 2020 - March 2022

- Deliver real-time, accurate oral translations and interpretations for clients
- Translation of documents and other written materials
- Provide accurate interpretation involving Spanish and English-speaking clients
- Completion of daily activity logs and other documentation

Billingual Administrative Assistant at Assurant

February 2017 - December 2020

- Establishing and maintaining official documents and records
- Provided assistance and support to Chief Executive Officer and Management Department.
- General bilingual support for international companies

Customer Service Specialist at Assurant

July 2015 - February 2017

- Receiving and placing customer service telephone calls
- Resolving customer complaints, managing database records, drafting status reports on customer service issues
- Data entry and research as required to troubleshoot customer problems

EDUCATION

Bachelor in English-Spanish Translation, Universidad de Montevideo

March 2020 - Present

Technical, Scientific and Audiovisual Specialization

Bachelor of Education, Universidad Tecnológica Nacional

March 2017 - December 2020